### Contactar

elwinlhq@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/elwinlhq (LinkedIn)

# Aptitudes principales

Java

**JavaScript** 

Java Enterprise Edition

## Languages

English (Professional Working)

Chinese (Elementary)

Quechua (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Mendeley Advisor

Masters degree

### Honors-Awards

First Prize in the Smart Destinations hackathon! (#Hack4SD)

Award to young leaders in action program "Emprende Ahora!"

Scholarship

First prize in the University Contest of Talent and Entrepreneurship "CHAMP-U"

Grant to participate in the meeting of Peruvian scientists in Europe "SINAPSIS 2017"

# Elwin Huaman

Researcher at STI Innsbruck

Insbruck

## Extracto

I work on researching of semantic web technologies within the academy and the industry. My main interests are knowledge graphs, knowledge curation, data enrichment, representation, visualization and the combination with related technologies such as machine learning and statistics.

# Experiencia

STI Innsbruck

Researcher

septiembre de 2018 - Present (2 años 4 meses)

Innsbruck, Austria

STI International is a global network engaging in research, education, innovation and commercialization activities on semantic technologies working to facilitate their use and applicability within industries and society as a whole. STI Innsbruck is at the University of Innsbruck engaged in research and development to bring information and communication technologies of the future into today's world.

### Quechua Experience

Founder

junio de 2017 - Present (3 años 7 meses)

Puno Province, Peru

QUECHUA EXPERIENCES are activities designed and led by inspiring Quechua families. They go beyond typical tourism by immersing guests in true Quechua family traditions. It's an opportunity for anyone to learn about their culture, traditions, or expertise without barriers.

See: https://quechuaexperience.github.io/

QUIPU [Quechua Language Knowledge Graph]

Founder

2019 - julio de 2020 (1 año)

Nunoa, Puno, Peru

With QUIPU we are trying to create a knowledge graph that can preserve as much as possible all the Quechua knowledge in a structured format.

See more: https://www.slideshare.net/elwinlhq/quipu-quechua-knowledge-graph-pilot-building-virtual-assistants-based-on-quechua-language

KIPU: Knowledge that Inspires People like you Founder septiembre de 2019 - marzo de 2020 (7 meses)

Imagine if we could speed up time in the fight against climate change:

[EN] KIPU is a knowledge engine, chatbot, web search engine and App that stores, evaluates, curates, and represents sustainable destinations.

[ES] KIPU es un motor de conocimiento (knowledge graph), chatbot (Kipu), buscador web (Smart Travel) y App (KipuLab) que almacena, evalúa, cura, y representa destinos sostenibles.

see more: https://www.slideshare.net/elwinlhq/kipu-knowledge-that-inspirespeople-like-you-sustainable-travel

RIC Bela krajina
Business Development
noviembre de 2017 - marzo de 2018 (5 meses)
Slovenia

Plan, organize and implement promotional and informative activities to promote tourism and business development in the villages of this region (Bela Krajina, Slovenia) using technologies like 3D printer, Oculus Rift.

Promote tourism through Google, TripAdvisor, WikiLoc, Geocaching and social networks. Advise and train startups in the Co-Working space, with the development of their skills and abilities necessary for the start-up of their company and support in web development and applications.

Universidad de Oviedo Researcher septiembre de 2014 - julio de 2017 (2 años 11 meses) Asturias, Spain studying and working as a researcher are my passions

University of Salamanca Research Analyst septiembre de 2013 - septiembre de 2014 (1 año 1 mes)

Page 2 of 4

Salamanca, España

researching and analyzing the human behavior, study the Cibermetria, social networks.

America Movil Peru SAC
Operations Analyst
enero de 2013 - junio de 2013 (6 meses)
Puno, Perú

Sales operations analyst to provide High-speed Internet through optical fiber. Also information management and support, Web site maintenance, etc.

Pre-University Centre of the National University of Altiplano – Puno, Public Education.

Assistant Systems noviembre de 2011 - mayo de 2013 (1 año 7 meses) Puno, Peru

Administration and management of the information of students and teachers, through the development of information systems, web applications and Educational web portal.

National University of Altiplano System Engineer noviembre de 2011 - abril de 2013 (1 año 6 meses) National University of Altiplano

Administration and management of the information of students and teachers, through the development of information systems, web applications and Educational web portal.

# Educación

Leopold-Franzens Universität Innsbruck

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Computer Science · (2018)

Universidad de Oviedo

Master's degree, Web Engineering (2014 - 2017)

Universidad de Salamanca Máster degree in Digital Information Systems, Ingeniería informática · (2013 - 2014) Universidad Nacional del Altiplano System Engineering, Engineering · (2008 - 2012)